Starting Treatment
On the day of your CT planning scan,
the radiation therapist will give you
a preliminary schedule of your radiation
treatment days and times.
You will return to the department
on the first day of treatment.
This first day will require a slightly
longer appointment than all the following
days, as there are extra steps
for setup verification as well as time
with the nurses in our clinic
to go over other important information,
such as things to do
and things to avoid while on treatment.
More detailed instructions about this
first day
will be given to you by the therapist
and your doctor.
After that, depending
on your personalized treatment schedule,
you may come back for treatment daily
or every other day,
or you may be done with treatment
altogether.
While our nurses and staff will discuss
other specific instructions with you,
you can generally go about your day
as you would otherwise.
Some individuals are concerned about
being around loved ones after treatment.
It is important to note that you are not
radioactive
after external beam radiation treatment.
You may shower, but do not
scrub the treated area.
Avoid sun exposure to the treated area
and use sunscreen.
Your skin in the treatment
area will be more sensitive to the sun.
Up to a year after treatment is completed.
Always remember that if you have
any questions throughout the journey,
our staff is available to help answer
any questions or provide guidance.
The journey can be very confusing,
and our goal is to help
make this just a bit easier to understand.